Bug bounty is easy, is what we think
when we first hear about it and
we see thousands of dollars being
awarded for not so complex bugs.
But is it really?
I'm not a person that started their
cybersecurity career 20 years ago, and
I didn't hack since primary school.
I was a regular dude who studied
computer science, started working as
a pentester, and two years ago I quit
to do bug bounty and create content.
I'm sharing with you
details of my journey.
And in this video, I will tell you
about my second year of bug bounty with
precise number of reports and earnings.
Enjoy!
One day I logged into my
WordPress website and I saw an alert(1).
At first, I thought it's some kind of
joke by a plugin developer, but turned
out that one of you tried an XSS payload
in the search field on my website.
And it didn't work for you but it
did trigger the XSS on the backend.
It was a zero day in MonsterInsights
plugin used by over 3 million
websites, which makes it one
of the most popular WordPress
plugins.
A bug like this is great because
not only you can report it to the
developers of the plugin, but also
to every single website that uses the
plugin and has a bug bounty program.
So you can get multiple
bounties for one bug.
And since this plugin was so popular,
I knew it's worth thousands of dollars.
I sort of wanted to to find out
who actually found it and let you
know that you just found the bug.
But it was just impossible to track who
initiated this search on my website.
So I decided to do it myself and I
collaborated with my friend Dawid,
who I knew does a lot of bug bounty
automations, which by the way are now
available as a product called Vidoc.
In total, we found 19 websites with
bug bounty programs using this plugin.
And we made.
We made $0 from it.
The problem was that it was quite a
complex blind XSS because  It triggered
in a very specific functionality and also
depended on the analytics backend used.
We just didn't get blind XSS pingbacks
to XSSHunter, and to be honest, I'm
still not exactly sure why, but in
hindsight, I should have spent more
time using this plugin with different
analytics backends to create a payload
suitable for every single integration.
One way or another, it was a huge
disappointment because in theory,
this bug affected 3 million websites
and I couldn't even make $1 out of it.
But it definitely made me hungry for
more scalable zero days like this.
Later, I was hacking on Discourse,
an open source forum, and among
other bugs, I found an XSS which I
knew I can report to many programs.
First, myself, I found one vulnerable
instance, and I got $2,000 from it.
It made me really happy and quite proud
because it was the first case of a
bounty for a scalable zero day and it
was a decent reward of $2,000 as well.
I also reached out to Nagli.
He's one of the best hackers out
there and he relies on automation.
He found two more instances.
So we filed two reports.
One of them is in the new
state since 10 months.
And the other one is quite interesting
because first, Bugcrowd triaged it.
But then it was closed
because of no CSP bypass.
We were confused with Nagli because we
only reported it to programs with no CSP
in place since we didn't have a bypass.
Turned out that they had planned to
enable CSP anyway, even before they
got our report and they implemented
it after Bugcrowd triaging our report
and before security team doing it.
But we opened a support ticket on
Bugcrowd  and they were quick to
respond and resolve the situation.
And we got $3,600 of
bounty for this report.
So shout out to the Bugcrowd team
for doing a great job here and to the
program as well, because they resolved
the situation, which was actually
just a unfortunate timing situation.
in total, I got $512 from the vendor,
$2,000 from one instance, and then
$3,600 split in half for another one.
And when collaborating, even
though technically you only get
50% of the bounty, you
are not actually losing anything.
Because if you find a zero day, what you
should do is first, you should try to
find all vulnerable instances yourself
and report it to them by yourself.
And only then, after you have no
more ideas on how to detect more,
Then you go to a person like Nagli
who does the automations and you
ask them to find more instances.
You are not losing anything because
you wouldn't find those instances
anyway, and the other person, of course,
also benefits, so everyone is happy.
So don't hesitate to contact
someone that does automations
when you find a scalable zero day.
For me, it was one of my goals.
And after achieving it, I decided
to switch things up a bit.
I invested more time into learning CodeQL.
It's not a regular bug bounty program,
but I will not go into details here
because I covered it in another video
and in multiple articles in BBRE Premium.
My investment paid out really well
because I got my highest bounty to
date of $5,500 for a CodeQL query to detect
arbitrary file write by ZipSlip.
And you may think that everything
just goes according to plan
for me, but it's not true.
Later, I also found an
authentication bypass in Mastodon.
They don't have a bug bounty program,
but I did it for the purpose of
writing another CodeQL query.
But because of some strange
things happening with Ruby,
I just couldn't make it work.
I also hacked on many different
regular bug bounty programs, but I
couldn't stick to one for long enough.
I also found an XSS in one
of the Google's products.
I got a 'Nice catch!' and the report
was triaged for a few weeks.
However, when deciding the reward,
they decided to reward me with $0.
It was actually a decision I could
understand, it was just quite painful
that this decision was made so
late when I was already expecting a
bounty of $3k or something like this.
Then there was another zero
day that I wanted to scale.
I stumbled upon the NodeBB forum
when doing one of the case studies I
found an XSS quite quickly, reported
it to the vendor and I started
looking for vulnerable instances.
I found one, and then I also collaborated
with Michael Ness to detect more.
one program closed it as informational,
the other one resolved it,
but without paying any bounty.
There was however one Bugcrowd program,
which I was really hopeful for.
They were active and
triaged the bug quickly.
We collaborated and I gave them the
monkey patch to fix the vulnerability
before the official fix is released.
I thought I will get a $1,500
payout from them.
At this point, it was a few months
after I came back to Poland after
winter in Tenerife, and I just couldn't
turn on the hacking mode again.
At this point, I would welcome any 4-digit bounty to break this dry spell.
but they only paid me $100, saying
they usually don't pay for zero
days at all, but they wanted to
reward me for good collaboration.
So, while it was a nice compliment
to hear, you know, I would
rather hear curse words with $1,500 bounty
So it turned out that the $256
reward from the vendor was my
highest bounty for this zero day.
So again, quite a lot
of disappointment here.
And in the bounty vlog one year ago,
I complained how little time I spent
on bug bounty and I planned to change.
And I did.
But not for the better, I spent little
time overall doing hacking, but even
worse, I jumped between programs a lot.
I didn't have the persistence, the
persistence, which I think is the number
one thing that every single experienced
hunter mentions in every single interview.
Like take a look at how many different
programs I've tried this year,
and the most time I spent on one.
is 40 hours, with a total of
barely over 200 hours of hunting.
So, in some sense, I'm closing in
on Tim Ferriss 4 hour workweek.
But jokes aside,
Remember, did I log my time
in a very specific way
and it doesn't make sense for you
to compare yourself to, to my time.
But it makes a lot of sense for me
to compare myself year over year.
And it is much less time
than in the previous year.
it's not easy making a video like
this, basically admitting to a lot
of procrastination and time wasting.
In fact, my friend, Dawid, whom I
mentioned before, had to sort of
convince me to do it because I was
like, "maybe, maybe I shouldn't".
But he reminded me that the goal of this
series is to give you the real image,
to tell you how it actually looks like,
even if it's not a quick success story,
My perspective also changed
a lot since last year.
Then, I felt quite insecure
about my income and I was very
disappointed with my time management.
But this year, I felt much more
stability and I allowed myself
to design the lifestyle that
I want and simply said, enjoy.
I travelled a lot. I spent over 100 days
in Spain, Portugal and others, met dozens
of great people and had lots of fun.
And in the moments of bitching myself for
not working more, I have to remind myself
that that's what I quit my 9 to 5 for.
Another complaint that I had to
myself was that I spent too much
time on the business side of
things and not enough time hunting.
This also has changed a lot because
since I started doing case studies in
BBRE Premium where I extract all the
reports about the particular bug class,
and I do the analysis. Since I've started
doing those, BBRE Premium really caught
traction and is now at the moment where
I could only live off that income.
It takes a lot of
pressure off my shoulders.
And I should probably also outsource
more to other people because I do
too much myself, but outsourcing is a
difficult skill, which I'm only learning.
And you know what?
Bug bounty may seem random at times, but
it does reward good work in the long run.
When I started hunting and I made $7,000
in 100 hours on the Stripe challenge, I
thought to myself, if I can make $7,000
out of a bunch of mediums, what will
happen when I find a $10,000 or a $15,000 critical?
And it did eventually happen, apart it
wasn't a $10,000 or $15,000 bug and it happened
in such a low time bounty-wise for me.
I got $20,000 for a path traversal on a
private program on Bugcrowd and it wiped
off completely any remaining pressure to
find bugs and also showed me that there
is no magic in those 5-digit payouts.
So in total, I more than doubled
the hourly rate in the second
year compared to the first year.
And I even increased the total income,
even though I had way fewer findings.
So can you live off bug bounties?
For me, there is absolutely no doubt that
if I shut down YouTube and BBRE premium
today, and I started focusing only on
bug bounty, I would make a great living.
The plan for the next year?
I'd really love to go
to a live hacking event.
In fact, I think it would work quite well
because I see that I'm just a horrible
multitasker and having to focus on a
live hacking event target for a few weeks
to then focus only on creating content
for a few weeks could work just well.
And also, I should outsource more to have
more time for hacking and I should stop
bitching myself for not working so much.
I want to keep traveling and digital
nomading and basically embrace my
twenties because sometimes I feel
like I'm too serious for my age.
I also urge you to design a lifestyle
that you want and not only blindly
follow the masses or social pressure.
I can tell you from my experience that
either running a business or doing
bug bounty with unreliable income
is not as scary as you might think.